Quico Blazquez Vidal

Game Programmer



- quicoblazquez@gmail.com
- Spain
- 23 years old

Links

Resume / Portfolio Website

Education

 Multimedia Engineering
(Digital Creation and Entertainment Itinerary)

> University of Alicante, Spain Sep 2019 - Jun 2023

Bachelor of Science

IES Enric Valor, Castalla Sep 2017 - Jun 2019

Languages

Spanish	
Catalan	
English	
Japanese	

Skills

OKIIIS	
Work ethic	
Teamwork	
Communication	
Coding	

Programming Languages

Debugging

Summary

Passionate video game programmer with experience in C++ and C#. Specializing in game engines and structures, I have developed custom tools and systems to enhance game development processes. I have collaborated on team prototypes and optimized performance using various algorithms and design patterns. I created a prototype from scratch, covering nearly all aspects, from physics and graphics engines to the ECS game engine and systems management.

In addition to this, I am dedicated to continuous improvement and strive to contribute more to the team with each project.

I am experienced with Unity, including developing dialogue systems and AI with GraphView. Additionally, I have worked with Unreal Engine and I am open to new opportunities leveraging my C++ expertise.

For more details on my projects and skills, please visit my website.

Work Experience

Game Programmer, GGTech Entertainment (Internship), Alicante, Spain

June 2023 - August 2023

- Enhanced skills by studying company resources.
- Developed a small Bomberman-like game using Unity's NavMesh for movement and a level editor for fast and efficient creation

Featured Projects

Morris.exe

October 2022 - November 2022

Arcade game created for Amstrad CPC where the challenge was programming gamthe game engine in **Z80 assembly language**. **The game was a finalist at the Valencia Indie Summit 2023.**

Prometheus: Ignis fur

2022 - 2023

Game prototype where I programmed and optimized to run on a machine with 2GB of RAM. This included creating game, physics and graphics engines from scratch using C++ and OpenGL.

Forest Blessing

2023 - Present

2.5D game in Unity Where i Cover all aspects connected to programming, form gameplay to editors to streamline the developmentt process.

Courses

Al: Behaviour Trees /// Design Patterns, Udemy